Guide to the New-York Historical Society Portrait Collection circa 1640-2020 (bulk, 1800-1950) PR 52
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Individuals and Family Groups, 59621
  - Subseries I.A. Individuals and Family Groups: Small Format, 59622
    - Cary, 60974 (Box 27)
    - Case, 60973 (Box 27)
    - Casey, 60972 (Box 27)
    - Cass, Lewis, 60971 (Box 27)
    - Catlin, 60970 (Box 27)
    - Caton, 60969 (Box 27)
    - Catt, Carrie Chapman, 60968 (Box 27)
    - Chamberlin, Clarence D., 60967 (Box 27)
    - Champe, 60966 (Box 27)
    - Chandler, 60965 (Box 27)
    - Chapin, 60964 (Box 27)
    - Chapin, E. H., 60963 (Box 27)
    - Chase, 60962 (Box 28)
    - Chase, Salmon P., 60961 (Box 28)
    - Chase, Samuel, 60960 (Box 28)
    - Chase, William Merritt (Box 28)
    - Cheney, 60959 (Box 28)
    - Child, 60958 (Box 28)
    - Child, Edmund Bramhall, 60957 (Box 28)
    - Childs, 60956 (Box 28)
    - Choate, Joseph H., 60955 (Box 28)
    - Choate, Rufus, 60954 (Box 28)
    - Christophe, Henri, 60953 (Box 28)
    - Church, 60952 (Box 28)
    - Clarendon, Edward Hyde (Lord Cornbury), 60951 (Box 28)
    - Clark, 60950 (Box 28)
    - Clark, George Rogers, 60949 (Box 28)
    - Clarke, 60948 (Box 28)
    - Clarkson, 60947 (Box 28)
    - Clay, 60946 (Box 28)
    - Clay, Henry, 60945 (Box 28)
      As a younger man
      As an older man
      Medals, busts, and monument
    - Clay, Henry and wife, 60942 (Box 28)
    - Clayton, 60941 (Box 29)
    - Clemens, Samuel L., 60940 (Box 29)
    - Cleveland, 60939 (Box 29)
    - Cleveland, Frances, 60938 (Box 29)
    - Cleveland, Grover, 60937 (Box 29)
    - Clinton, DeWitt, 60936 (Box 29)
    - Clinton, George, 60935 (Box 29)
    - Clinton, George (with original autograph fragment, undated) (Box 29)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Gift of Jeanette Sarkasian Wagner, February 2019.
    - Clinton, George and wife, 60934 (Box 29)
    - Clinton, Henry, 60933 (Box 29)
    - Clinton, James, 60932 (Box 29)
    - Cobb, 60931 (Box 29)
    - Cobb, Howell, 60930 (Box 29)
    - Cochran, 60929 (Box 29)
    - Cochrane, Thomas, 60928 (Box 29)
    - Codrington, Edward, 60927 (Box 30)
    - Cody, William F., 60926 (Box 30)
    - Coffin, 60925 (Box 30)
    - Coke, Thomas, 60924 (Box 30)
    - Colden, Cadwallader, 60923 (Box 30)
    - Cole, 60922 (Box 30)
    - Colfax, Schuyler, 60921 (Box 30)
    - Collingwood, Cuthbert, 60920 (Box 30)
    - Collins, 60919 (Box 30)
    - Collyer, 60918 (Box 30)
    - Columbus, Christopher (2 folders), 60917 (Box 30)
    - Conner, 60916 (Box 30)
    - Cook, 60915 (Box 30)
    - Cook, James, 60914 (Box 30)
    - Cooke, 60913 (Box 30)
    - Coolidge, Calvin, 60912 (Box 30)
    - Cooper, 60911 (Box 31)
    - Cooper, James Fenimore, 60910 (Box 31)
    - Cooper, Peter (2 folders), 60909 (Box 31)
    - Corcoran, Michael, 60908 (Box 31)
    - Cornell, 60907 (Box 31)
    - Cornwallis, Charles Marquis, 60906 (Box 31)
    - Cornwallis, William (Box 31)
    - Couch, 60905 (Box 31)
    - Cox (2 folders), 60904 (Box 31)
    - Cox, Eliza Pilcher, 60903 (Box 31)
    - Cox, J. Dolson, 60902 (Box 31)
    - Cox, John Vance, 60901 (Box 31)
    - Cox, Mary Eliza, 60900 (Box 31)
    - Cox, Samuel Hanson, 60899 (Box 31)
    - Cox, Townsend, 60898 (Box 31)
    - Cox, Townsend, Jr., 60897 (Box 31)
    - Crane, 60896 (Box 32)
    - Crawford, 60895 (Box 32)
    - Crawford, Samuel W., 60894 (Box 32)
    - Crawford, William H., 60893 (Box 32)
    - Cresswell, P. M. G., 60892 (Box 32)
    - Crispell, John Bell, 60891 (Box 32)
    - Crittenden, 60890 (Box 32)
    - Crittenden, J. J., 60889 (Box 32)
    - Crocker, 60888 (Box 32)
    - Crocker, Marcellus M., 60887 (Box 32)
    - Crockett, David, 60886 (Box 32)
    - Cromwell, 60885 (Box 32)
    - Cromwell, Oliver, 60884 (Box 32)
    - Crook, George, 60883 (Box 32)
    - Crosby, 60882 (Box 32)
    - Crosby, Howard, 60881 (Box 32)
    - Crosby, John Schuyler, 60880 (Box 32)
    - Cruger, 60879 (Box 32)
    - Curtin, 60878 (Box 33)
    - Curtis, 60877 (Box 33)
    - Curtis, George William, 60876 (Box 33)
    - Curtis, Roger, 60875 (Box 33)
    - Curtis, Samuel R., 60874 (Box 33)
    - Cushing, 60873 (Box 33)
    - Cushing, Caleb, 60872 (Box 33)
    - Cushing, William B., 60871 (Box 33)
    - Custer, George Armstrong, 60870 (Box 33)
    - Cutting, 60869 (Box 33)
    - Da-Dz miscellaneous (23 folders), 60868 (Box 34-36)
    - Dahlgren, John A., 60867 (Box 37)
    - Dahlgren, Ulric, 60866 (Box 37)
    - Dale, Richard, 60865 (Box 37)
    - Dallas, George M., 60864 (Box 37)
    - Dana, Charles A., 60863 (Box 37)
    - Danforth, 60862 (Box 37)
    - Davidson, 60861 (Box 37)
    - Davie, 60860 (Box 37)
    - Davies, 60859 (Box 37)
    - Davis, 60858 (Box 37)
    - Davis, Jefferson, 60857 (Box 37)
    - Davis, Jefferson Columbus, 60856 (Box 37)
    - David, Charles H., 60855 (Box 37)
    - Dawes, Charles, 60854 (Box 37)
    - Day, 60853 (Box 37)
    - Dayton, William L., 60852 (Box 37)
    - Dean, 60851 (Box 37)
    - Dean, Silas, 60850 (Box 37)
    - DeKay, James E., 60849 (Box 37)
    - Delacroix, 60848 (Box 37)
    - Delafield, 60847 (Box 37)
    - Delano, 60846 (Box 37)
    - DeLoosey (see Havemeyer/deLoosey family), 60845 (Box 37)
    - Depew, Chauncey, 60844 (Box 37)
    - De Peyster, 60843 (Box 38)
    - De Peyster, Abraham and wife, 60842 (Box 38)
    - Derby, 60841 (Box 38)
    - Deven, Charles, 60840 (Box 38)
    - Dewey, George, 60839 (Box 38)
    - Dewey, Thomas, 60838 (Box 38)
    - Dewitt, 60837 (Box 38)
    - Dexter, 60836 (Box 38)
    - Dickinson, 60835 (Box 38)
    - Dickinson, John, 60834 (Box 38)
    - Dix, 60833 (Box 38)
    - Dix, John A., 60832 (Box 38)
    - Dodge, 60831 (Box 38)
    - Dodge, Grenville N., 60830 (Box 38)
    - Dodge, William E., 60829 (Box 38)
    - Dorr, 60828 (Box 38)
    - Doubleday, Abner, 60827 (Box 38)
    - Douglas, 60826 (Box 39)
    - Douglas, Stephen A., 60825 (Box 39)
    - Downing, 60824 (Box 39)
    - Doyle, 60823 (Box 39)
    - Drake, Francis, 60822 (Box 39)
    - Draper, 60821 (Box 39)
    - Drayton, 60820 (Box 39)
    - Drayton, P., 60819 (Box 39)
    - Drayton, W. H., 60818 (Box 39)
    - Drowne, 60817 (Box 39)
    - Dubois, 60816 (Box 39)
    - Duckworth, John Thomas, 60815 (Box 39)
    - Dudley, 60814 (Box 40)
    - Dudley, Horace E., 60813 (Box 40)
    - Dudley, Horace E., family, 60812 (Box 40)
    - Duff, 60811 (Box 40)
    - Duffy, James Edmund, 60810 (Box 40)
    - Duke, Tony, 60809 (Box 40)
    - Duncan, Adam (Viscount Duncan), 60808 (Box 40)
    - Dunlap, 60807 (Box 40)
    - Dunsmore, John Ward, 60806 (Box 40)
      In costume
      In studio, exhibition and studios
      Portraits, general
      Self-portraits (photographs of paintings)
    - Dupont, Samuel F., 60802 (Box 40)
    - Durand, 60801 (Box 40)
    - Duryee, Abram, 60800 (Box 40)
    - Dutcher, 60799 (Box 40)
    - Duyckinck, 60798 (Box 40)
    - Dwight, 60797 (Box 40)
    - Dyer, 60796 (Box 40)
    - Ea-Ez miscellaneous (9 folders), 60795 (Box 41)
    - Eames, Wilberforce, 60794 (Box 42)
    - Early, Jubal, 60793 (Box 42)
    - Eaton, 60792 (Box 42)
    - Eddy, 60791 (Box 42)
    - Edison, Thomas Alva and Mina, 60790 (Box 42)
    - Edmunds, 60789 (Box 42)
    - Edwards, 60788 (Box 42)
    - Edwards, George Wharton, 60787 (Box 42)
    - Edwards, Jonathan, 60786 (Box 42)
    - Egan, William Bradshaw, 60785 (Box 42)
    - Eglinton, 60784 (Box 42)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 60783 (Box 42)
    - Eliot, Charles W., 60782 (Box 42)
    - Eliott, George Augustus (Lord Heathfield), 60781 (Box 42)
    - Ellett, Charles, 60780 (Box 42)
    - Elliott, 60779 (Box 42)
    - Ellis, 60778 (Box 42)
    - Ellsworth, Elmer E., 60777 (Box 43)
    - Ellsworth, Oliver, 60776 (Box 43)
    - Elsberg, Louis, 60775 (Box 43)
    - Elphinstone, George Keith, 60774 (Box 43)
    - Ely, 60773 (Box 43)
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 60772 (Box 43)
    - Emmett, Thomas Addis, 60771 (Box 43)
    - English, 60770 (Box 43)
    - English, William H., 60769 (Box 43)
    - Ericsson, John, 60768 (Box 43)
    - Erskine, 60767 (Box 43)
    - Evans, 60766 (Box 43)
    - Evans, Robley D., 60765 (Box 43)
    - Evarts, William M., 60764 (Box 43)
    - Everett, Edward, 60763 (Box 43)
    - Ewell, Richard, 60762 (Box 43)
    - Ewing, 60761 (Box 43)
    - Fa-Fz miscellaneous (19 folders), 60760 (Box 44-45)
    - Fairbanks, 60759 (Box 46)
    - Fairchild, 60758 (Box 46)
    - Fairfax, 60757 (Box 46)
    - Fanning, 60756 (Box 46)
    - Farmer, Sarah I., 60755 (Box 46)
    - Farnham, 60754 (Box 46)
    - Farragut, David Glasgow, 60753 (Box 46)
      Monuments and memorials
      Portraits
    - Farrar, 60751 (Box 46)
    - Fenton, Reuben, 60750 (Box 46)
    - Ferguson, 60749 (Box 46)
    - Ferris, 60748 (Box 46)
    - Ferry, 60747 (Box 46)
    - Fessenden, 60746 (Box 46)
    - Field, 60745 (Box 46)
    - Field, Cyrus West, 60744 (Box 46)
    - Fillmore, Millard, 60743 (Box 46)
    - Finley, 60742 (Box 47)
    - Fish, 60741 (Box 47)
    - Fish, Hamilton, 60740 (Box 47)
    - Fish, Nicholas, 60739 (Box 47)
    - Fish, Stuyvesant and Marian, 60738 (Box 47)
    - Fisher, 60737 (Box 47)
    - Fisk, 60736 (Box 47)
    - Fitch, 60735 (Box 47)
    - Fletcher, 60734 (Box 47)
    - Flower, 60733 (Box 47)
    - Floyd, 60732 (Box 47)
    - Foch, Ferdinand, 60731 (Box 47)
    - Foote, 60730 (Box 47)
    - Forbes, 60729 (Box 47)
    - Ford, 60728 (Box 47)
    - Forrest, 60727 (Box 47)
    - Forrest, N. B., 60726 (Box 47)
    - Forsyth, 60725 (Box 47)
    - Foster, 60724 (Box 48)
    - Foster, John G., 60723 (Box 48)
    - Foster, Stephen, 60722 (Box 48)
    - Fowler, 60721 (Box 48)
    - Fox, 60720 (Box 48)
    - Fox, Charles James, 60719 (Box 48)
    - Francis, John W., 60718 (Box 48)
    - Francis, Joseph, 60717 (Box 48)
    - Franklin, 60716 (Box 48)
    - Franklin, Benjamin, 60715 (Box 48)
      Bust-length portraits with glasses
      Bust-length portraits without glasses
      Embossed paper portraits
      Full-length portraits
      Scenes from life
      Sculpture – busts
      Sculpture – full-length
    - Franklin, John, 60708 (Box 49)
    - Franklin, William B., 60707 (Box 49)
    - Franks, Jacob and family, 60706 (Box 49)
    - Frelinghuysen, Theodore, 60705 (Box 49)
    - Fremont, John C., 60704 (Box 49)
    - French, 60703 (Box 49)
    - Fry, 60702 (Box 49)
    - Fulton, Robert, 60701 (Box 49)
    - Fuller, 60700 (Box 49)
    - Furman, 60699 (Box 49)
    - Ga-Gz miscellaneous (# folders?), 60698 (Box 50-52)
    - Gage, Thomas, 60697 (Box 53)
    - Gagner family, 60696 (Box 53)
    - Gaines, Edmund Pendleton, 60695 (Box 53)
    - Gallatin, 60694 (Box 53)
    - Gallatin, Albert, 60693 (Box 53)
    - Gallatin, Albert Eugene, 60692 (Box 53)
    - Gallatin, Frederic, 60691 (Box 53)
    - Gansevoort, 60690 (Box 53)
    - Gardiner, 60689 (Box 53)
    - Gardner, Alan, 60688 (Box 53)
    - Garfield, James A., 60687 (Box 53)
    - Garfield, Lucretia Rudolph, 60686 (Box 53)
    - Garibaldi, Guiseppe, 60685 (Box 53)
    - Garland, 60684 (Box 53)
    - Garrett, 60683 (Box 54)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd, 60682 (Box 54)
    - Gates, 60681 (Box 54)
    - Gates, Horatio, 60680 (Box 54)
    - Genet, 60679 (Box 54)
    - Gerry, Elbridge, 60678 (Box 54)
    - Gibson, 60677 (Box 54)
    - Gilbert, 60676 (Box 54)
      Related Materials
      For a group portrait of a dinner thrown by F.W. Woolworth in honor of architect Cass Gilbert, see Subseries II.B. Groups: Medium format, Commercial activities, Businesses.
    - Gillmore, Quincy A., 60675 (Box 54)
    - Gilman, 60674 (Box 54)
    - Girard, Stephen, 60673 (Box 54)
    - Gladstone, William Ewart, 60672 (Box 54)
    - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 60671 (Box 55)
    - Goldsborough, Louis M., 60670 (Box 55)
    - Goldsmith, Oliver, 60669 (Box 55)
    - Goodwin, 60668 (Box 55)
    - Gordon, 60667 (Box 55)
    - Gordon, John B., 60666 (Box 55)
    - Gough, John B., 60665 (Box 55)
    - Gould, 60664 (Box 55)
    - Gould, Helen and children, 60663 (Box 55)
    - Gould, Jay, 60662 (Box 55)
    - Graham, 60661 (Box 55)
    - Granger, 60660 (Box 55)
    - Grant, 60659 (Box 55)
    - Grant, Frederick D. and family, 60658 (Box 55)
    - Grant, Hugh, 60657 (Box 55)
    - Grant, Ulysses S., 60656 (Box 56)
      Album of his life, circa 1886
      Funeral procession, 1885 August 8
      ....As military officer and in uniform: photographs
      ....As military officer and in uniform: prints
      ....As President and civilian: photographs
      ....As President and civilian: prints
      ....In uniform with full beard, 1861
      ....With family members
      ....With family - group portraits and homes
      Tombs and memorial photographs
    - Graves, 60646 (Box 57)
    - Gray, 60645 (Box 57)
    - Greeley, Horace, 60644 (Box 57)
    - Green, 60643 (Box 57)
    - Greene, 60642 (Box 57)
    - Greene, George Sears, 60641 (Box 57)
    - Greene, Nathaniel, 60640 (Box 57)
    - Gregg, 60639 (Box 57)
    - Gregory, 60638 (Box 57)
    - Gresham, Walter O., 60637 (Box 57)
    - Griffin, 60636 (Box 57)
    - Griffith, 60635 (Box 57)
    - Griffith, Frederick, 60634 (Box 57)
    - Griswold, 60633 (Box 58)
    - Grosvenor, 60632 (Box 58)
    - Grover, 60631 (Box 58)
    - Grundy, Felix, 60630 (Box 58)
    - Guggenheim, 60629 (Box 58)
    - Gunn, 60628 (Box 58)
    - Gunther, 60627 (Box 58)
    - Gurney, 60626 (Box 58)
    - Ha-Hz miscellaneous (31 folders), 60625 (Box 59-61)
    - Habersham, 60624 (Box 62)
    - Hale, 60623 (Box 62)
    - Hale, Edward Everett, 60622 (Box 62)
    - Hale, Nathan, 60621 (Box 62)
    - Hall, 60620 (Box 62)
    - Halleck, Fitz-Green, 60619 (Box 62)
    - Halleck, Henry W., 60618 (Box 62)
    - Hamilton, 60617 (Box 62)
    - Hamilton, Alexander, 60616 (Box 62)
      Sculpture
    - Hamilton, Elizabeth Schuyler, 60614 (Box 62)
    - Hamlin, Hannibal, 60613 (Box 62)
    - Hammond, 60612 (Box 62)
    - Hampton, Wade, 60611 (Box 62)
    - Hancock, John, 60610 (Box 63)
    - Hancock, Winfield Scott, 60609 (Box 63)
    - Harbord, J. G., 60608 (Box 63)
    - Hardee, William J., 60607 (Box 63)
    - Harding, Warren Gamaliel, 60606 (Box 63)
    - Hardinge, 60605 (Box 63)
    - Hardy, 60604 (Box 63)
    - Hardy, Charles, 60603 (Box 63)
    - Hare, 60602 (Box 63)
    - Harlan, 60601 (Box 63)
    - Harle, 60600 (Box 63)
    - Harmon, 60599 (Box 63)
    - Harper, 60598 (Box 63)
    - Harris, 60597 (Box 63)
    - Harrison, 60596 (Box 63)
    - Harrison, Benjamin and family, 60595 (Box 63)
    - Harrison, William Henry and Anna Symmes, 60594 (Box 63)
    - Harsen, 60593 (Box 64)
    - Hart, 60592 (Box 64)
    - Hastings, 60591 (Box 64)
    - Hatch, 60590 (Box 64)
    - Hauptmann, 60589 (Box 64)
    - Hawke, Edward, 60588 (Box 64)
    - Hawley, 60587 (Box 64)
    - Hay, 60586 (Box 64)
    - Hay, John, 60585 (Box 64)
    - Hayes, 60584 (Box 64)
    - Hayes, Rutherford B. and Lucy, 60583 (Box 64)
    - Hayne, 60582 (Box 64)
    - Hays, 60581 (Box 64)
    - Hazen, W. B., 60580 (Box 64)
    - Heathcote, Caleb, 60579 (Box 64)
    - Heintzelman, Samuel P., 60578 (Box 64)
    - Hendricks, Thomas A., 60577 (Box 64)
    - Henry, 60576 (Box 65)
    - Henry, Patrick, 60575 (Box 65)
    - Henry, Thomas S. and wives, 60574 (Box 65)
    - Hervey, 60573 (Box 65)
    - Hewitt, 60572 (Box 65)
    - Hewitt, Abram Stevens, 60571 (Box 65)
    - Hickok, Wild Bill, 60570 (Box 65)
    - Hicks, 60569 (Box 65)
    - Hicks, Elias, 60568 (Box 65)
    - Higgins, 60567 (Box 65)
    - Hill (2 folders), 60566 (Box 65)
    - Hill, A. P., 60565 (Box 65)
    - Hitchcock, E. A., 60564 (Box 65)
    - Hobart, 60563 (Box 66)
    - Hobson, Richmond Pearson, 60562 (Box 66)
    - Hodges, 60561 (Box 66)
    - Hoffman, 60560 (Box 66)
    - Hoffman, Eugene A., 60559 (Box 66)
    - Hoffman, John T., 60558 (Box 66)
    - Holden, 60557 (Box 66)
    - Holland, 60556 (Box 66)
    - Holmes, 60555 (Box 66)
    - Holmes, Louise Allen, 60554 (Box 66)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 60553 (Box 66)
    - Holt, 60552 (Box 66)
    - Hone, Philip, 60551 (Box 66)
    - Hood, 60550 (Box 66)
    - Hood, Alexander, 60549 (Box 66)
    - Hood, John B., 60548 (Box 66)
    - Hood, Samuel, 60547 (Box 66)
    - Hooker, Joseph, 60546 (Box 67)
    - Hoover, Herbert Clark, 60545 (Box 67)
    - Hopkins, 60544 (Box 67)
    - Hopkins, Ellen Dunlap, 60543 (Box 67)
    - Hopkinson, 60542 (Box 67)
    - Hosmer, 60541 (Box 67)
    - Hotchkiss, 60540 (Box 67)
    - Houston, 60539 (Box 67)
    - Houston, Samuel, 60538 (Box 67)
    - Howard, 60537 (Box 67)
    - Howard, Charles, 60536 (Box 67)
    - Howard, Harry, 60535 (Box 67)
    - Howard, Oliver O., 60534 (Box 67)
    - Howe, 60533 (Box 67)
    - Howe, Richard, 60532 (Box 67)
    - Howell, 60531 (Box 68)
    - Howells, 60530 (Box 68)
    - Howland, 60529 (Box 68)
    - Howland, Henry Elias (2 folders), 60528 (Box 68)
    - Hoyt, 60527 (Box 68)
    - Hubbard, 60526 (Box 68)
    - Hubbard, Gurdon S. and wife, 60525 (Box 68)
    - Hudson, 60524 (Box 68)
    - Hughes, 60523 (Box 68)
    - Hughes, Charles Evans, 60522 (Box 68)
    - Hughes, Edward, 60521 (Box 68)
    - Hull, 60520 (Box 69)
    - Humboldt, Alexander von, 60519 (Box 69)
    - Humphrey, 60518 (Box 69)
    - Humphreys, 60517 (Box 69)
    - Hunt, 60516 (Box 69)
    - Hunter, 60515 (Box 69)
    - Hunter, David, 60514 (Box 69)
    - Hunter, Robert M. T., 60513 (Box 69)
    - Hunter, Thomas, 60512 (Box 69)
    - Huntington, 60511 (Box 69)
    - Huntington, Samuel, 60510 (Box 69)
    - Hutton, 60509 (Box 69)
    - Hyacinthe, Pere, 60508 (Box 69)
    - Hyde, 60507 (Box 69)
    - Hyde, James Hazen, 60506 (Box 69)
      James Hazen Hyde and related photos removed to Hyde Papers, December 2019.
    - Ia-Iz miscellaneous (3 folders), 60505 (Box 70)
    - Ingalls, 60504 (Box 70)
    - Ingersoll, 60503 (Box 70)
    - Ingersoll, Robert, 60502 (Box 70)
    - Inman, 60501 (Box 70)
    - Irving, Washington, 60500 (Box 70)
    - Irwin, 60499 (Box 70)
    - Ives, 60498 (Box 70)
    - Ja-Jz miscellaneous (7 folders), 60497 (Box 71)
    - Jackson, 60496 (Box 72)
    - Jackson, Andrew (2 folders), 60495 (Box 72)
    - Jackson, James, 60494 (Box 72)
    - Jackson, Stonewall (Thomas J.), 60493 (Box 72)
    - Jackson, William Hicks, 60492 (Box 72)
    - James, 60491 (Box 72)
    - James, Arthur C., 60490 (Box 72)
    - James, D. Willis and Ellen, 60489 (Box 72)
    - James, Henry, 60488 (Box 72)
    - Jay, 60487 (Box 72)
    - Jay, John, 60486 (Box 72)
    - Jefferson, Thomas (3 folders), 60485 (Box 73)
    - Jenkins, 60484 (Box 73)
    - Jensen, Gustav, 60483 (Box 73)
    - Joan of Arc, 60482 (Box 73)
    - Johnson (2 folders), 60481 (Box 73)
    - Johnson, Andrew and Eliza, 60480 (Box 73)
    - Johnson, Hosmer A., 60479 (Box 73)
    - Johnson, Reverdy, 60478 (Box 73)
    - Johnson, Samuel, 60477 (Box 73)
    - Johnson, William, 60476 (Box 73)
    - Johnston, 60475 (Box 74)
    - Johnston, Albert S., 60474 (Box 74)
    - Johnston, Joseph Eggleston, 60473 (Box 74)
    - Jones (2 folders), 60472 (Box 74)
    - Jones, Catesby, 60471 (Box 74)
    - Jones, Jacob, 60470 (Box 74)
    - Jones, John Paul, 60469 (Box 74)
      Sculptures, scenes from life, etc.
    - Jones, Samuel J., 60467 (Box 74)
    - Jordan, 60466 (Box 74)
    - Jouett, James E., 60465 (Box 74)
    - Judd, Norman B., 60464 (Box 74)
    - Judson, 60463 (Box 74)
    - Ka-Kz miscellaneous (11 folders), 60462 (Box 75)
    - Kalbfleisch, 60461 (Box 76)
    - Kane, 60460 (Box 76)
    - Kearny, 60459 (Box 76)
    - Kearny, Philip, 60458 (Box 76)
    - Keats, 60457 (Box 76)
    - Keene, 60456 (Box 76)
    - Kelby, 60455 (Box 76)
    - Kelley, 60454 (Box 76)
    - Kellogg, 60453 (Box 76)
    - Kelly, 60452 (Box 76)
    - Kempenfelt, Richard, 60451 (Box 76)
    - Kendall, 60450 (Box 76)
    - Kendall, William Sargeant, 60449 (Box 76)
    - Kendrick, Henry Lane, 60448 (Box 77)
    - Kennedy, 60447 (Box 77)
    - Kennedy, John P., 60446 (Box 77)
    - Kent, James, 60445 (Box 77)
    - Keppel, Augustus, 60444 (Box 77)
    - Kerfoot, 60443 (Box 77)
    - Keteltas, 60442 (Box 77)
    - Key, 60441 (Box 77)
    - Keyes, Erasmus D., 60440 (Box 77)
    - Kilpatrick, Judson, 60439 (Box 77)
    - Kimball, 60438 (Box 77)
    - Kimball, Le Roy E., 60437 (Box 77)
    - King (2 folders), 60436 (Box 78)
    - King, Charles, 60435 (Box 78)
    - King, Rufus and Mary Alsop, 60434 (Box 78)
    - Kip, 60433 (Box 78)
    - Kirk, 60432 (Box 78)
    - Knapp, 60431 (Box 78)
    - Knight, 60430 (Box 78)
    - Knox, 60429 (Box 78)
    - Knox, Henry, 60428 (Box 78)
    - Koch, Edward, 60427 (Box 78)
    - Koehn/Kolhn family, 60426 (Box 78)
    - Kosciuszko, Thaddeus, 60425 (Box 78)
    - Kossuth, Louis, 60424 (Box 78)
    - Kretsch, 60423 (Box 78)
    - La-Lz miscellaneous (19 folders), 60422 (Box 79-80)
    - Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier, marquis de (3 folders), 60421 (Box 81)
    - LaGuardia, Fiorello, 60420 (Box 81)
    - Lamar, Lucius Quintus Cincinnatus, 60419 (Box 81)
    - Lamb, 60418 (Box 81)
    - Lamont, 60417 (Box 81)
    - Lander, Frederick W., 60416 (Box 81)
    - Lane, 60415 (Box 81)
    - Langdon, 60414 (Box 81)
    - Langdon, John, 60413 (Box 81)
    - La Rochefoucauld-Liancourt, Francois-Alexandre-Frederic, duc de, 60412 (Box 81)
    - Laurence, 60411 (Box 81)
    - Laurence, Abbott, 60410 (Box 81)
    - Laurens, Henry, 60409 (Box 81)
    - Law, 60408 (Box 81)
    - Lawrence, 60407 (Box 81)
    - Lawrence, James, 60406 (Box 81)
    - Lebrun, Albert, Madame, 60405 (Box 82)
    - Lee, 60404 (Box 82)
    - Lee, Fitzhugh, 60403 (Box 82)
    - Lee, Henry, 60402 (Box 82)
    - Lee, Robert E., 60401 (Box 82)
    - Lehman, 60400 (Box 82)
    - Leland, 60399 (Box 82)
    - Lentilhon, 60398 (Box 82)
    - Leonard, 60397 (Box 82)
    - Lequier family, 60396 (Box 82)
    - Levy, 60395 (Box 82)
    - Lewis, 60394 (Box 82)
    - Lewis, Morgan, 60393 (Box 82)
    - Lexow, Clarence, 60392 (Box 82)
    - Lincoln, Abraham, 60391 (Box 83)
      Death and funeral processions
      Memorials, tributes, caricatures, and allegorical prints
      McClure Collection portfolios
      Photographs
      Prints
      ....Ephemera
      ....Portraits: bust-length without beard
      ....Portraits: bust-length with beard
      ....Portraits: group, with cabinet members
      ....Portraits: group, with family members
      ....Portraits: profile
      ....Portraits: seated
      ....Portraits: standing
      ....Portraits: photographs (19th century) of prints
      Residences
      ....Illinois
      ....Kentucky
      Scenes from the life of
      Twentieth-century portraits
    - Lincoln, Abraham (continued), 60390 (Box 84)
      Bagoe Collection of mounted and captioned copy photographs
      ....Loose (unmounted) photographs
      ....Youth and early life
      ....Political career
      ....Civil War scenes
      ....Gettysburg dedication (1863)
      ....Assassination at Ford's Theatre/deathbed scenes
    - Lincoln, Abraham (continued), 60389 (Box 85)
      Bagoe Collection of mounted and captioned copy photographs (continued)
      ....Funeral and tomb
      ........Processions, train, etc.
      ........New York City scenes
      ....Conspirators chase and trial
      ....Execution of conspirators
    - Lincoln, Benjamin, 60371 (Box 86)
    - Lincoln, Mary Todd, 60370 (Box 86)
    - Lincoln, Robert Todd, 60369 (Box 86)
    - Lindbergh, Charles A., 60368 (Box 86)
    - Lindsay, John Vliet (2 folders), 60367 (Box 86)
    - Little, 60366 (Box 86)
    - Livingston, 60365 (Box 86)
    - Livingston, Edward, 60364 (Box 86)
    - Livingston, Philip, 60363 (Box 86)
    - Livingston, Robert R., 60362 (Box 86)
    - Livingstone, Belle, 60361 (Box 86)
    - Lockley, 60360 (Box 86)
    - Lockley, Fred and Hope, 60359 (Box 86)
    - Logan, 60358 (Box 86)
    - Logan, John A. and wife, 60357 (Box 86)
    - Long, 60356 (Box 86)
    - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth and children, 60355 (Box 86)
    - Longstreet, James, 60354 (Box 87)
    - Lord, 60353 (Box 87)
    - Loughborough, Alexander, 60352 (Box 87)
    - Low, 60351 (Box 87)